Board of Governors fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Committees, 1968-2009; F-33-8
  - Presidential Search and Review Committees, 1968-2009; F-33-8-1; 73 cm of textual records
    - 1968-1979 Presidential Search Committees, F-33-8-1-1; 12 cm of textual records
      The Board's first three Presidential Search Committees were formed in 1968, in 1973, and 1978, to recommend candidates for the position of University President. This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the Presidential searches and subsequent appointments that occurred during these dates. Includes correspondence, agendas, minutes, terms of reference, procedures, lists of candidates, curriculum vitae, reports, press releases, and clippings.
      No further accruals are expected.
      - Terms of Reference, 1968-1973; F-33-8-1-1-1 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Committee nominations: support papers, 1968-1973; F-33-8-1-1-2 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1969; F-33-8-1-1-3 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Board of Governor's minutes, 1969; F-33-8-1-1-4 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Student involvement: minutes and papers, 1968-1969; F-33-8-1-1-5 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - List of candidates, 1969; F-33-8-1-1-6 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Candidate short list and support papers, 1968-1969; F-33-8-1-1-7 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Terms of Reference: support papers, 1968-1973; F-33-8-1-1-8 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1973-1974; F-33-8-1-1-9 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
      - Search committee procedures and composition, 1975-1979; F-33-8-1-1-10 (Archival box - standard 33-82)
    - 1992 Presidential Search Committee, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2; 27.2 cm of textual records, 1 floppy disk (textual records)
      This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the Presidential search and subsequent appointment made in 1992.
      Textual records; Textual records in electronic form (digitized)
      Includes 1 floppy disk, located in file F-33-8-1-2-7.
      - Correspondence and papers, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-1 (Archival box - standard 33-165)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/3, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-2 (Archival box - standard 33-165)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/3, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-3 (Archival box - standard 33-165)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 3/3, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-4 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - Nominations and correspondence, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-5 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - Candidate list and correspondence, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-6 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - NAUBCS Conference participant list and advertisements, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-7 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
        Textual records; Records in electronic form (born-digital)
      - C-list nominations and applications, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-8 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - Consultant proposals, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-9 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - Post-search correspondence, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-10 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - B-list nominations and applications, candidate list 1/2, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-11 (Archival box - standard 33-166)
      - B-list nominations and applications, candidate list 2/2, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-12 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Post-search feedback, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-13 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Candidate lists, committee meeting minutes and papers 1/2, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-14 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Candidate lists, committee meeting minutes and papers 2/2, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-15 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Landmark Consulting, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-16 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Interview weekend and short-listed candidate CV's, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-17 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Candidate itinerary, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-18 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - SFU information packages, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-19 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Committee member information, 1992-1993; F-33-8-1-2-20 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
    - Policies and Terms of Reference, 1993-2007; F-33-8-1-3; 3.1 cm of textual records
      This sub-sub-series comprises records related to the creation and updating of policies and terms of reference for both the Presidential Search Committees and the Committees to Review the President Prior to Reappointment. The records include terms of reference, procedures, memos, and correspondence.
      Further accruals may occur.
      - Terms of Reference, Committee to Review President Prior to Reappointment, 1991-1996; F-33-8-1-3-1 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Terms of Reference, Presidential Search Committee, 1993-1995; F-33-8-1-3-2 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
      - Presidential Search Committee Policy Review, 2007; F-33-8-1-3-3 (Archival box - standard 33-167)
    - Committee to Review President Jack Blaney Prior to Reappointment, 1995-2000; F-33-8-1-4; 1.6 cm of textual records
      This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the Committee’s review of President Jack Blaney’s performance, in consideration of reappointment.
      - Correspondence, contract, and review papers, 1995-2000; F-33-8-1-4-1 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
    - Committee to Review President John Stubbs Prior to Reappointment, 1996-2001; F-33-8-1-5; 4.7 cm of textual records
      This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the Committee’s review of President John Stubbs' performance, in consideration of reappointment.
      - President John Stubbs performance review, 1995-1996; F-33-8-1-5-1 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
      - Contract renewal and objectives, 1995-2001; F-33-8-1-5-2 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
      - Correspondence, report, and memos, 1996-1997; F-33-8-1-5-3 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
    - 1999 Presidential Search Committee, 1999-2000; F-33-8-1-6; 3.1 cm of textual records
      This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the Presidential search and subsequent appointment made in 1999.
      - Correspondence and memos; meeting agendas and papers; and terms of reference, 1999-2000; F-33-8-1-6-1 (Archival box - standard 79)
      - Itineraries and catering records, 1999-2000; F-33-8-1-6-2 (Archival box - standard 79)
    - 2004 Committee to Review President Michael Stevenson Prior to Reappointment, 2004-2009; F-33-8-1-7; 21 cm of textual records, 1 audio cassette (ca. 1 hr.)
      The Committee was established in November 2004 with the purpose of reviewing President Dr. Michael Stevenson for reappointment. This sub-sub-series comprises records related to this specific activity and includes memos, reports, correspondence, notes, policies, agreements, contracts, as well as committee meeting agendas, minutes, and other supporting documents.
      Textual records; Sound recordings
      Includes 1 cassette tape, located in file F-33-8-1-7-9.
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-1 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-2 (Archival box - standard 33-168)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 3/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-3 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 4/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-4 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 5/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-5 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 6/6, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-6 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-7 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - Letters of support and committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2004-2005; F-33-8-1-7-8 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - President Michael Stevenson performance review 1/4, 1999-2009; F-33-8-1-7-9 (Archival box - standard 33-169)
      - President Michael Stevenson performance review 2/4, 1999-2009; F-33-8-1-7-10 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
      - President Michael Stevenson performance review 3/4, 1999-2009; F-33-8-1-7-11 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
      - President Michael Stevenson performance review 4/4, 1999-2009; F-33-8-1-7-12 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
  - Employee Relations Committee, 1983-2006; F-33-8-2; 23.2 cm of textual records
    This sub-series contains records created by the Employee Relations Committee in fulfillment of its responsibilities concerning salary policies, material changes, and framework agreements. These records also encompass the approval and reporting on negotiating parameters, collective agreements, and policies associated with employee groups' terms of employment, as well as the establishment, termination, or adjustment of pension and employee benefit plans. The records include meeting agendas and minutes, correspondence, reports, contracts, and bargaining agreements.
    Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Employee Relations Committee; Textual records
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/4, 1983-1989; F-33-8-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/4, 1983-1989; F-33-8-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 3/4, 1983-1989; F-33-8-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 4/4, 1983-1989; F-33-8-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 33-170)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/3, 1989-1992; F-33-8-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/3, 1989-1992; F-33-8-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 3/3, 1989-1992; F-33-8-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1993; F-33-8-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1994-1995; F-33-8-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1996-1999; F-33-8-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2000-2003; F-33-8-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 33-171)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2001-2006; F-33-8-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2004-2006; F-33-8-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
  - Investment Advisory Committee, 1985-2006; F-33-8-3; 19.6 cm of textual records
    Also called the Advisory Committee on University Investments, the Investment Advisory Committee was formed to provide investment advice and oversight to the University treasury function. The Committee was also responsible to act in an advisory capacity to the Board on investment matters. This sub-series consists of records related to the Committee’s advisory activities. Includes committee meeting agendas, minutes, and papers including reports; memos; correspondence; and policies.
    Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Investment Advisory Committee; Textual records
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 1991-1993; F-33-8-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 1991-1993; F-33-8-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1994-1996; F-33-8-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1997; F-33-8-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1998-2000; F-33-8-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 33-172)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2001-2003; F-33-8-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2001-2003; F-33-8-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Committee meeting minutes, 2002-2006; F-33-8-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2004-2005; F-33-8-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2004-2005; F-33-8-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2006; F-33-8-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
  - Signature Authorization Committee, 1986-2006; F-33-8-4; 5.9 cm of textual records
    Formed in 1986, the Signature Authorization Committee was a standing committee empowered to appoint signing officers of the University. The Committee was active until it was dissolved and had its responsibilities absorbed by the Finance and Administration Committee in 2004. This sub-series consists of records related to signing authorization activities pre-2004. Includes memos; correspondence; meeting agendas and minutes; guidelines, procedures and terms of reference; as well as contracts and agreements.
    - Committee meeting minutes, agendas and papers, 1986-2008; F-33-8-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-173)
    - Contracts and agreements 1/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
    - Contracts and agreements 2/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
  - 25th Anniversary Advisory Committee, 1988-1989; F-33-8-5; 4.2 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. 25th Anniversary Advisory Committee
    This sub-series comprises records created during the activities of the 25th (or Silver) Anniversary Advisory Committee and the 25th Anniversary Implementation Committee, along with all their associated sub-committees. The Silver Anniversary Advisory Committee was established to plan events and celebratory activities in honor of SFU's 25th anniversary, with the theme "SFU - 25 years of making a difference in your life." The records include committee meeting agendas and minutes, memos, reports, budget projections, project plans, and correspondence.
    - Committee meeting minutes, agendas and papers 1/2, 1988-1989; F-33-8-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
    - Committee meeting minutes, agendas and papers 2/2, 1988-1989; F-33-8-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
  - Executive Committee, 1989-2003; F-33-8-6; 10.4 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Executive Committee
    This sub-series consists of records related to the activities of the Executive Committee. This standing committee served to exercise all powers and perform all duties of the Board of Governors in the case of urgent matters where it was not possible to wait for a scheduled Board meeting. The Executive Committee later merged with the Compensation Committee to form one entity. Includes meeting agendas and minutes, curriculum vitae, memos, contracts, proposals, and correspondence.
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1989-1993; F-33-8-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 1994-2003; F-33-8-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-174)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 1994-2003; F-33-8-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
  - Joint University APSA Committee, 1990-1999; F-33-8-7; 2.1 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Joint University APSA Committee
    The JUAC sub-committee brought the University together with the Administrative and Professional Staff Association (APSA) to collaboratively address matters related to administrative policies. This sub-series consists of records related to this Committee's work creating and revising administrative policies. Includes memos, policies, procedures, agreements, and correspondence.
    - Memos and administrative policy revision, 1990-1999; F-33-8-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
  - Compensation Committee, 1991-2006; F-33-8-8; 12 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Compensation Committee
    The Compensation Committee was formed in 1989 for the purposes of determining the annual salaries of senior administrative executives whose positions did not fall under existing agreements or salary administration policies. This included the President, VP Academic, and VP Finance. At the time of formation, the Committee’s membership included: the Board Chair as Chair of the Committee, the Chair of the Administration/Finance Committee, and the Chair of the Employee Relations Committee. The Compensation Committee later became one entity with the Employee Relations Committee. This sub-series contains records related to the formation, evolution, and work of this committee. Includes meeting agendas and minutes; correspondence; and memos.
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1989-1993; F-33-8-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 1994-1995; F-33-8-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-175)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 1994-1995; F-33-8-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1996-1999; F-33-8-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2000-2003; F-33-8-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-8-0-6 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2004-2006; F-33-8-8-0-7 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
  - Ad Hoc Board Governance Committee, 1994-1995; F-33-8-9; 1.6 cm of textual records
    This sub-series consists of records related to the activities of the Ad Hoc Board Governance Committee. Formed in 1994, the Ad Hoc Board Governance Committee served to develop policies on Board Governance and bring recommendations to the Board. Includes memos, policies, and meeting agendas.
    - Committee meeting agendas and papers, 1994-1995; F-33-8-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
  - Revenue Enhancement Task Force, 1994-1995; F-33-8-10; 1.6 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Revenue Enhancement Task Force
    This sub-series consists of records created by the Revenue Enhancement Task Force in fulfilling its mandate to review existing sources of operating revenue, consider potential sources of new revenue, and bring recommendations to the Board on an operating revenue enhancement strategy for the future. Includes memos; classified advertisements; reports including drafts, final copies, and working notes; correspondence; and terms of reference.
    - Task force report and papers, 1994-1995; F-33-8-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
  - Committee on the Chancellor's Distinguished Service Awards, 1994-2001; F-33-8-11; 1.6 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Committee on the Chancellor's Distinguished Service Awards
    This sub-series contains records related to the activities of the Committee on the Chancellor's Distinguished Service Awards. This Committee was formed to review nominations and select recipients for the annual Chancellor's Distinguished Service Award as well as to recommend criteria and policy to support the awarding process. Includes memos; correspondence; articles; meeting agendas and minutes; recipient lists; terms of reference; and curriculum vitae.
    Furher accruals are expected.
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1994-2000; F-33-8-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-176)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1999-2007; F-33-8-11-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
    - Nomination letters, 2000-2001; F-33-8-11-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
  - Executive Search and Review Committees, 1995-2000; F-33-8-12; 8.4 cm of textual records
    This sub-series comprises records created by the Search and Review Committees tasked with the responsibilities of reappointment or recruitment, nomination, and recommendation for the appointment of vice-presidents and departmental deans. The records encompass meeting agendas and minutes, curriculum vitae, terms of reference, correspondence, and other relevant supporting documents.
    - Vice-President, Research and Dean, Graduate Studies Search Committee, 1995-1996; F-33-8-12-1; 2.1 cm of textual records
      This sub-sub-series consists of records related to the search and subsequent appointments made for the positions of Vice President, Research and Dean, Graduate Studies.
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 1995-1996; F-33-8-12-1-1 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
    - 2001 Vice-President, Research Search Committee, 2000-2001; F-33-8-12-2; 6.3 cm of textual records
      The Vice-President, Research Search Committee was formed to oversee the reappointment or recruitment, nomination, and recommendation for appointment of a candidate for the position of Vice-President, Research. Records in this sub-sub-series relate to these activities as well as to the nomination and selection of committee members. Includes meeting agendas and minutes, curriculum vitae, terms of reference, and correspondence.
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2000-2001; F-33-8-12-2-1 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
      - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2000-2001; F-33-8-12-2-2 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
      - Letters of support for reappointment, 2000-2001; F-33-8-12-2-3 (Archival box - standard 33-177)
  - Audit Committee, 1995-2004; F-33-8-13; 25 cm of textual records; Simon Fraser University. Board of Governors. Audit Committee
    The Audit Committee functioned as a standing committee with the responsibility of recommending the approval of annual financial statements to the Board of Governors. It also received the Audit Report from the Provincial Auditor General, oversaw the Internal Audit Report, and monitored the Annual Insurance and Risk Management Report. Additionally, the committee recommended approval of policies related to asset insurance.
    This sub-series comprises records associated with the committee's tasks and includes meeting agendas and minutes, reports, financial statements, terms of reference, and correspondence.
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/4, 1985-1993; F-33-8-13-0-1 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/4, 1985-1993; F-33-8-13-0-2 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 3/4, 1985-1993; F-33-8-13-0-3 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 4/4, 1985-1993; F-33-8-13-0-4 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 1994-2000; F-33-8-13-0-5 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 1994-2000; F-33-8-13-0-6 (Archival box - standard 33-178)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 1/2, 2001-2003; F-33-8-13-0-7 (Archival box - standard 33-179)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers 2/2, 2001-2003; F-33-8-13-0-8 (Archival box - standard 33-179)
    - Committee meeting agendas, minutes and papers, 2003-2006; F-33-8-13-0-9 (Archival box - standard 33-179)